# **SUSAN EVANS**

# **UX Designer + Developer**

susanev.com hello@susanev.com (206) 395-8146

Three years experience leading UX Design and Research. Five years experience innovating in the computer science education space.

I have a diverse background in UX Design and code and am passionate about improving the human experience by combining deep technical and design knowledge to craft digital experiences.

I love solving challenging problems in diverse teams while using user-centered practices.

# **SKILLS**

DesignToolsRapid prototypingSketchWireframingAxure RPUI designIllustratorInteraction designIndesignWeb designPhotoshop

#### **Programming**

Java Competitive analysis
Python Survey Design
Ruby on Rails Interviews
JavaScript Usability studies
HTML & CSS Participatory Design

Research

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## **User Experience Designer**

University of Washington LiY! Feb 2014 – Mar 2016

Designed and usability tested a tool for faculty across the nation to use when creating workshops focused on the advancement of women and underrepresented groups in engineering fields.

## Web Designer

**PSCSTA** 

Mar 2014 – Jun 2015

Led the redesign of a website for computer science teachers and students, which included user research, usability studies, implementation and evaluation. Improving access and awareness in the community.

#### **User Researcher**

Ubi Interactive

Dec 2014 – Mar 2015

Collaborated in a student team to conduct user research and usability studies on Ubi's software installation process. All of our recommendations were implemented by Ubi.

# **Computer Science Lecturer**

University of Washington CSE

Mar 2016 – Present

Design and teach undergraduate and graduate introductory programming courses using a variety of languages including Java, Processing and p5.js.

# **Computer Science Instructor**

Seattle Public Schools

Sep 2011 – Sep 2015

Led the creation of a rigorous, supportive, 4-year cs program in an ethnically diverse and low-income South Seattle school, which emphasized authentic learning, exploration, and community involvement.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **University of Washington**

MS in Human Centered Design & Engineering Graduated Jun 2016

#### **University of Arizona**

BS in Computer Science and Mathematics Graduated Dec 2008